synapseindia.com 2019-04-07

# SynapseIndia Privacy Policy

This privacy policy has been developed to better serve those who are concerned with how their 'Personally identifiable information' (PII) is being used online. PII is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person. Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or manage your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website.

  * ## What personal information do we collect from the people that visit our blog, website or app?

When ordering or registering on our site, you may be asked to enter your name, email address, mailing address, phone number or other details to help you with your experience.

  * ## When do we collect information?

We collect information from you when you fill out a form or enter information on our site.

  * ## How do we use your information?

We collect information from you when you register, make a purchase, sign up for our newsletter, respond to a survey, explore the website or use certain other site features in the following ways:

\- To allow us to better service you in responding to your customer service requests.  
\- To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature.  
\- To send periodic emails regarding your order or other products and services.
  * ## How do we protect visitor information?

Our website is scanned on a regular basis for security holes and known vulnerabilities in order to make your visit to our site as safe as possible.

  * ## We do not use Malware Scanning.

Your personal information is contained behind secured networks and is only accessible by a limited number of persons who have special access rights. In addition, all sensitive/credit information you supply is encrypted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology. 

We implement a variety of security measures when a user enters, submits, or accesses their information to maintain the safety of your personal information. All transactions are processed through a gateway provider and are not stored or processed on our servers.

  * ## Website Cookies

We do not use cookies for tracking purposes. You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser (like Internet Explorer) settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser's Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies.

If you disable cookies, some features will be disabled that make your site experience more efficient and some of our services will not function properly. However, you can still place orders.

  * ## Third-party disclosure

We do not sell, trade, or transfer your personally identifiable information to outside parties.

  * ## Third-party links

We do not include or offer third-party products or services on our website.

  * ## How does our site handle do not track signals?

We honor do not track signals and do not track plant cookies, or use advertising when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place.

  * ## Does our site allow third-party behavioral tracking?

It's also important to note that we do not allow third-party behavioral tracking

  * ## COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)

When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under 13, the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, the nation's consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children's privacy and safety online. 

We do not specifically market to children under 13.

  * ## Fair Information Practices

The Fair Information Practices Principles form the backbone of privacy law in the United States and the concepts play a significant role in the development of data protection laws around the globe. Understanding the Fair Information Practice Principles and how they should be implemented is critical to comply with the various privacy laws that protect personal information.

  * ## Individual Redress Principle

We also agree to the Individual Redress Principle, which requires that individuals have a right to pursue legally enforceable rights against data collectors and processors who fail to adhere to the law. This principle requires not only that individuals have enforceable rights against data users, but also that individuals have recourse to courts or government agencies to investigate and/or prosecute non-compliance by data processors.

  * ## CAN-SPAM Act

The CAN-SPAM Act is a law that sets the rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them, and spells out tough penalties for violations. 

If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, you can email us at info@synapseindia.com and we will promptly remove you from ALL correspondence.
